<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Francisco Cruzado Perni</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Francisco Cruzado Perni</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2016-{year}. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 17:59:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LAMBDA functions - Build your own Excel formulas easily</title><link>/posts/excel-lambda-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 17:59:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/excel-lambda-functions/</guid><description>You could create your own Excel functions using VBA since long time ago, but there is a new way of creating them: LAMBDA functions.
As of today, this option is only available for Office Insiders participants, but it will be soon available to the general public.
The LAMBDA function official documentation is great but let me show you how this works with an actual example. Imagine that you have a requirement where you need to calculate something as easy as the days that are left in the month for a given date.</description></item><item><title>Create a Hugo Blog and connect it with Google Analytics</title><link>/posts/hugo-blog-with-ga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 17:59:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/hugo-blog-with-ga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creating a blog with &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hugo&lt;/a>
&lt;/strong> and hosting it in &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Pages&lt;/a>
&lt;/strong> is easy. I am not going to explain it because you have this wonderful &lt;a href="https://www.panicoenlaxbox.com/post/hugo-github/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post&lt;/a>
by &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/panicoenlaxbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@panicoenlabox&lt;/a>
&lt;/strong>, who explains it perfectly and it is the one that I followed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Storytelling with Power BI</title><link>/posts/data-storytelling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 16:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/data-storytelling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block" alt="Power BI" src="/images/power-bi.jpg" loading="lazy"
width="534" height="230"
style="width: 256px;height: 128px" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many tools for creating data visualizations, but one of the most common used and powerful is Power BI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Visualization with Power BI</title><link>/posts/data-visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 13:54:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/data-visualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in the era of data. We are surrounded by data. There are tons of tools, methodologies, software, processes, etc. to extract, transform and load from just a couple or records to even tens of millions of records. But what about after all that? How can we make so much data usable?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>JoinCsv</title><link>/posts/joincsv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:59:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/joincsv/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block" alt="CSV" src="/images/csv.png" loading="lazy"
width="128" height="128"
style="width: 128px;height: 128px" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was my first utility written in Python, when I was learning the basics before going deep into the Databricks world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Francisco Cruzado Perni is an Associate professor at IE and a Lead Development Engineer in Analitycalways, designing and developing software for the retail sector.
Formerly he worked as Senior Software Engineer and Analyst at Haitong Bank, a Chinese investment bank, where he managed software and database projects.
Previously Francisco held a Senior Consultant role for different organizations inside the public administration, such as Patrimonio Nacional and Ministerio de Economía y Hacienda; as well as in the finance sector (Banco Santander).</description></item></channel></rss>