<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Francisco Cruzado Perni</title><link>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Francisco Cruzado Perni</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2016-{year}. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 16:20:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Storytelling with Power BI</title><link>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/data-storytelling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 16:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/data-storytelling/</guid><description>To Be Translated
There are many tools for creating data visualizations, but one of the most common used and powerful is Power BI.
In the previous edition we learned how to create effective visualizations in Power BI to display insights existing on data, showing information extracted from logs recorded in App Insights of an API hosted in Azure.
In this edition we will learn what is the structure of a good story, the steps to create it and how to build a compelling story using Power BI to highlight the information that lies underneath our data.</description></item><item><title>Data Visualization with Power BI</title><link>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/data-visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 13:54:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/data-visualization/</guid><description>To Be Translated
We live in the era of data. We are surrounded by data. There are tons of tools, methodologies, software, processes, etc. to extract, transform and load from just a couple or records to even tens of millions of records. But what about after all that? How can we make so much data usable? The key is to extract the inner insights existing on data, and the best way to detect, identify and transmit insights is visualization.</description></item><item><title>JoinCsv</title><link>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/joincsv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:59:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://ocoloco.net/es/posts/joincsv/</guid><description>To Be Translated
This was my first utility written in Python, when I was learning the basics before going deep into the Databricks world.
This program will join all the csv files of a folder in a single one.
Default folder is &amp;ldquo;csv&amp;rdquo; and default output file is &amp;ldquo;joined.csv&amp;rdquo;.
Available options:
1 -h --help Display this help screen. 2 -f --folder Sets the folder that contains the files. 3 -o --output Sets the name of the output file.</description></item></channel></rss>