<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Francisco Cruzado Perni</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Francisco Cruzado Perni</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2016-{year}. All Rights Reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 12:20:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Eliminando el ruido de nuestras visualizaciones</title><link>/posts/decluttering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 12:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/decluttering/</guid><description>Una vez más he tenido el placer de poder hablar sobre visualización de datos, gracias al grupo Power Platform Euskadi. En esta ocasión ha sido en el Global Power Platform Bootcamp 2023 donde he podido hablar sobre técnicas para eliminar el ruido de nuestras visualizaciones, utilizando Power BI.
En la parte inferior encontraréis enlaces a los datasources, visualizaciones y presentación usadas durante la charla y, en el futuro, pondré un enlace al vídeo de la presentación.</description></item><item><title>LAMBDA functions - Build your own Excel formulas easily</title><link>/posts/excel-lambda-functions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 16:59:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/excel-lambda-functions/</guid><description>You could create your own Excel functions using VBA since long time ago, but there is a new way of creating them: LAMBDA functions.
As of today, this option is available for the general public, but this option was only available for Office Insiders participants when this post was released on 2022.
The LAMBDA function official documentation is great but let me show you how this works with an actual example.</description></item><item><title>Power BI: Gimme more visualizations!</title><link>/posts/more-visualizations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 16:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/more-visualizations/</guid><description>Within the Power BI Days Bilbao and the Power BI Virtual Conf 23, I had the pleasure to deliver the following content.
In the world of data visualization, simplicity is synonymous with success. But sometimes we want to go a little further and experiment with new visual models.
Power BI offers by default a lot of options with which we will cover most of our needs, but there is a MarketPlace with endless options to create different visualizations.</description></item><item><title>Create a Hugo Blog and connect it with Google Analytics</title><link>/posts/hugo-blog-with-ga/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 17:59:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/hugo-blog-with-ga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Creating a blog with &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hugo&lt;/a>
&lt;/strong> and hosting it in &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">GitHub Pages&lt;/a>
&lt;/strong> is easy. I am not going to explain it because you have this wonderful &lt;a href="https://www.panicoenlaxbox.com/post/hugo-github/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">post&lt;/a>
by &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/panicoenlaxbox" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@panicoenlabox&lt;/a>
&lt;/strong>, who explains it perfectly and it is the one that I followed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Storytelling with Power BI</title><link>/posts/data-storytelling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 16:20:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/data-storytelling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block" alt="Power BI" src="/images/power-bi.jpg" loading="lazy"
width="534" height="230"
style="width: 256px;height: 128px" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are many tools for creating data visualizations, but one of the most common used and powerful is Power BI.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Visualization with Power BI</title><link>/posts/data-visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 13:54:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/data-visualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in the era of data. We are surrounded by data. There are tons of tools, methodologies, software, processes, etc. to extract, transform and load from just a couple or records to even tens of millions of records. But what about after all that? How can we make so much data usable?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>JoinCsv</title><link>/posts/joincsv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 21:59:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/joincsv/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block" alt="CSV" src="/images/csv.png" loading="lazy"
width="128" height="128"
style="width: 128px;height: 128px" />
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was my first utility written in Python, when I was learning the basics before going deep into the Databricks world.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>